So here we are back with our flex container and our three items inside of it,
ها نحن نعود إلى الحاوية المرنة والعناصر الثلاثة بداخلها.
and now we're going to try different ways to reorder these items.
سنجرب عددًا من الطرق المختلفة لإعادة ترتيب هذه العناصر.
So we see now our order is box one,
نلاحظ أنها مرتبة كالآتي: المربع واحد،
box two, box three.
ثم المربع اثنان ثم المربع الثالث.
So the simplest way to reorder it is that we can literally here in our code,
أبسط طريقة لإعادة الترتيب باستخدام البرمجة
I can just move box two up so that now it's box two,
وذلك بتحريك برمجة المربع اثنان للأعلى، فيصبح الترتيب اثنان،
box one, box three,
ثم المربع واحد ويليه المربع ثلاثة،
and in our browser now we see box two,
ونراها في المتصفح كذلك المربع اثنان،
box one, box three.
ثم المربع واحد، ويليه المربع ثلاثة.
That's simply by moving the HTML itself from following lines.
فعلنا ذلك بنقل سطور برمجة HTML وتغيير مكانها
So let's put this back, so one, two,
لنعد هذا إلى مكانه، فتصبح واحد، اثنان،
three as our HTML read,
ثلاثة حسب برمجة HTML
and now let's do it with order.
والآن، سنغير الترتيب باستخدام رتبة Order
The way that the order works is that it's relative,
تعمل هذه الخاصية بشكل نسبي
so it'll be an evaluation where if I give
بحيث تنظر إلى القيم المختلفة وتقيّمها، فعندما أعطي
one and two in order of two but three in order of one,
واحد واثنين الرتبة اثنين، والمربع ثلاثة الرتبة واحد،
it means three will come first followed by one and two,
فهذا يعني أن ثلاثة سيأتي أولًا، يتبعه واحد واثنان،
and that one and two with a shared order of two,
وبما أن واحد واثنان يتقاسمان الرتبة اثنان،
which one of those comes first will then be thrown down to where it shows up in the HTML.
فسيعتمد أيهما سيظهر أولًا على مكان ظهورهما في HTML.
So let's take a look at this,
لنلق نظرة على هذا،
and now we see that box three is first because it has the order property of
نلاحظ أن المربع ثلاثة هو الأول لأنه يحمل خاصية الرتبة
one while two and one have the order property of two which is the lower value.
واحد، بينما المربعان اثنان وواحد لديهما خاصية الرتبة اثنان، وهي القيمة الأقل.
This property, they could share a three, a seven,
هذه الخاصية، يمكن أن تشارك ثلاث، أو سبعة،
it's all an evaluation of comparatively which has the
فكل ذلك هو تقييم للمقارنة بين القيمة
lowest one being low value and that would come first.
الأقل والتي ستظهر أولًا.
So now we have two ways to move things which are moving in the HTML itself,
لدينا طريقتان لنقل الأشياء من خلال تحريكها في برمجة HTML
the order property, and the third way that we can do this
أو خاصية الرتبة order، أما الطريقة الثالثة
is with the flex direction of the parent container.
فمن خلال الاتجاه المرن للحاوية الرئيسية.
So with flex direction row we have box three,
عند ضبط الاتجاه المرن إلى صف الاتجاه المرن، يكون لدينا المربع ثلاثة،
box one, box two,
ثم المربع واحد، ويليه المربع اثنان.
but with flex direction row reverse,
ولكن عند  ضبط الاتجاه المرن على عكس الصف،
we have box two,
يصبح لدينا المربع اثنان،
box one, box three.
ثم المربع واحد، ويليه المربع ثلاثة.
So those are the three different ways that you can order your elements.
هذه هي الطرق الثلاثة لترتيب العناصر.
You can either use the flex direction, flipping row,
يمكنك أن تستخدم ضبط الاتجاه المرن، وأن تقلب الصف،
and row reverse which will just reverse or setback the order in which they're laid out.
ويعمل عكس الصف على عكس الترتيب الذي وضعت فيه العناصر.
We have the specific order property of each of
كما أن لدينا خاصية الرتبة المحددة لكل
the items in a container which here are set to two and two,
عنصر في الحاوية، والتي نلاحظ أن قيمتها محددة باثنين واثنين،
and the one makes this one show up first so the order will be three,
وهنا رقم واحد يجعل هذه تظهر أولًا، وبالتالي يكون الترتيب ثلاثة،
two, one based on that.
اثنان، واحد.
The third way that you can order elements using
الطريقة الثالثة لترتيب العناصر باستخدام فليكس
flex is simply by doing it in the HTML itself.
فعن طريق برمجة HTML
So what do you think will happen now?
برأيكم ماذا سيحدث إذا
I've given div three an order of one,
أعطيت القسم (div) ثلاثة الرتبة واحد،
div two an order of two,
والقسم (div) اثنان الرتبة اثنين،
and div one an order of three.
والقسم (div) واحد الرتبة ثلاثة؟
So what order do we think the boxes will show up in?
فما هو الترتيب الذي ستظهر به المربعات برأيكم؟
Three, two, one. Did you get that?
ثلاثة، اثنان، واحد. هل فهمتم هذه الجزئية؟
You'll pick it up, I promise.
ستتقنونها سريعًا، أنا واثق من ذلك.